A Guide to the Documents from the County Manager's Library, 1889-1994
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
- Human Services
  - Child Care & Education
    - Forum on Children & Youth, Child Care Counselor, 1950 (Box 18)
    - White House Conference on Children & Youth (with correspondence, articles, schedules), 1950 (Box 18)
    - Crippled Children's Clinic (operations & equipment) Department of Public Health, 1950 (Box 18)
    - Minimum Standards for Kindergarten & Grade One, Arlington Preschool Association, 1951 (Box 18)
    - New Crippled Children's Building, Department of Public Health, 1951 (Box 18)
    - Bibliography, Arlington Preschool Minimum Standards, 1952 (Box 18)
    - Administrative Action Team-Youth Health, Welfare, 1967 (Box 18)
    - Youth, Health & Welfare, Task Force Report, 1968 (Box 18)
    - Day Care for Children, Commission on Human Resources, 1970 (Box 18)
    - Child Care Advisory Committee Report (with correspondence), 1972 (Box 18)
    - County Child Care Policy, Ad Hoc Committee Report (draft), 1974 (Box 19)
    - County Child Care Policy (final), 1974 (Box 19)
    - 1978 Summer Program for Youth, Evaluation, Department of Personnel (Box 19)
    - Children & Youth Mental Health Services Planning, Report, 1979 (Box 19)
  - Services for the Handicapped
    - Opening Doors for Handicapped Persons, Department of Human Resources, 1980 (Box 19)
    - Opening Doors - Appendices, 1980 (Box 19)
    - Opening Doors - Executive Summary, 1980 (Box 19)
    - Directory of Services for Disabled Persons, Department of Human Resources, 1980 (Box 19)
    - Happiness is a Barrier-Free Community, Study, Department of Human Resources, 1980 (Box 19)
  - Community Organization Files (correspondence, bulletins, etc.)
    - Community Council, 1944-1956 (Box 20)
    - Child Care Counselor, 1945-1956 (Box 20)
    - Arlington Guidance Clinic, 1947-1953 (Box 20)
    - Arlington Health & Welfare Council, 1950-1953 (Box 20)
    - Mental Hygiene Society, 1949-1954 (Box 20)
    - Interservice Club Council, 1954 (Box 20)
    - Family Service of Northern Virginia, 1953-1956 (Box 20)
  - Mental Health Grant
    - Funding for Community Mental Health & Mental Retardation Programs, FY71-72, Interim Application, Commission on Human Resources, 1969 (Box 20)
    - Community Mental Health & Mental Retardation Services Board, Initial Budget, 1970 (Box 20)
    - FY 1980 Grant Application, Community Mental Health, (1st file) (Box 20)
    - FY 1980 Grant Application (2nd file) (Box 20)
  - Dissertations
    - History & Organization of Services in Arlington County Department of Public Welfare, Robert J. Walsh, 1949 (Box 20)
    - The Experience of a Selected Number of Agencies in Arlington, Alexandria & Fairfax with Temporary Shelter for Children, Patricia J. Wood, 1951 (Box 20)
  - Department of Public Health Publications, 1950
    - Cancer Program (Box 20)
    - Child Health Services (Box 27)
    - Crippled Children's Program (Box 20)
    - Bureau of Inspection - Sanitation (Box 20)
    - Bureau of Laborities (Box 20)
    - Mental Hygiene Program, Arlington Guidance Center (Box 21)
    - Bureau of Public Health Nursing (Box 21)
    - The Tuberculosis Control Program (Box 21)
    - Veneral Disease Control Program (Box 21)
    - Vital Statistics (Box 21)
  - Other Pamphlets, Reprints
    - Annual Reports, Community Council, 1946, 1947 (Box 21)
    - "The Welfare Worker," April 1951 Department of Welfare & Institutions, Richmond (Box 21)
    - Arlington County's Program for Crippled Children, H. P. Ramsay, Medical Annals of District of Columbia, 1954 (Box 21)
    - A Survey of Dog Bites in Arlington, S. P. Mayers, Jr & R. G. Beachley, VA Medical Monthly, July 1955 (Box 21)
    - Visiting Nurse Association Fact Sheet (with leaflet), 1960 (Box 21)
    - Arlington Hospital brochures (2), 1960 (Box 21)
    - Department of Health booklet, 1966 (Box 21)
    - Department of Human Resources booklet, 1969 (Box 21)
    - Community Resources in Arlington for the Aging, Commission on Aging, 1970 (Box 21)
    - Serving Human Needs, Department of Human Resources, 1972 (Box 21)
    - First 12 Years, Senior Citizens' Day Center, 1976 (Box 21)
    - Arlington Hospital information kit, 1979 (2 photos, see APPENDIX) (Box 21)
    - Youth Services Handbook, Bureau of Labor & Training Services, 1983 (Box 21)
    - Buckingham Nursery and Kindergarten, Inc. Manual, n.d. (Box 21)
    - Arlington Preschool Association (booklet, leaflet, no dates) (Box 21)
- Subgroup 5
  - Citizen Information
    - Citizen's Handbook, 1976 (Box 21)
    - Courtroom Procedure (no date) (Box 21)
    - Crime Resistance Unit Information Packet (no date) (Box 21)
    - Police Week Pamphlet, 1967 (Box 21)
  - Rules and Regulations
    - Accident Investigation Outline (no date) (Box 21)
    - Manual of Rules and Regulations, 1956 (Box 21)
    - Police Beneficiary Association By-Laws (no date) (Box 21)
    - Rules and Regulations, 1972 (Box 21)
    - Sheriff's Manual for the Jail, 1964 (Box 21)
  - Police Services and Equipment
    - A Survey of Police Automotive Equipment, 1957 (Box 21)
    - A Study of Police Services for Children, 1968 (Box 21)
    - A Study of the Investigations Division, 1974 (Box 21)
    - Evaluation Report of Foot Patrol Program, 1975 (Box 22)
    - Traffic Safety Report, Book 1, 1948 [includes photographs] (Box 22)
    - Traffic Safety Report, Book 2, 1948 (1) (Box 22)
    - Traffic Safety Report, Book 2, 1948 (2) (Box 22)
    - Traffic Safety Report, Book 1, 1950 (1) (Box 22)
    - Traffic Safety Report, Book 1, 1950 (2) (Box 22)
    - Traffic Safety Report, Book 2, 1950 (Box 22)
    - Traffic Safety Report, Book 1, 1951 (1) (Box 22)
    - Traffic Safety Report, Book 1, 1950 (2) (Box 23)
    - Traffic Safety Report, Book 2, 1951 (1) (Box 23)
    - Traffic Safety Report, Book 3, 1951 (2) (Box 23)
  - Administration
    - County Manager's comments on Police Investigating Committee Report, 1950 (Box 23)
    - The Police Department (Analysis of Operations), 1950 (Box 23)
    - Report of Police Advisory Committee to County Board, 1968 (Box 23)
  - Planning
    - Arlington County Criminal Justice Workplan, 1976 (Box 23)
  - Community Relations
    - Survey of Residents' Perceptions of Criminal Justice System, 1972 (Box 23)
    - Survey of Victims and Witnesses of Felony Crimes, 1978 (Box 23)
- Parks, Recreation, and Community Resources
  - Reports
    - Recreational Survey, 1940-1941 (Box 23)
    - Arlington Recreation Council Report, 1947 (Box 23)
    - Proposed Recreation Program, 1948 (Box 23)
    - Department of Recreation Annual Report, 1948-1949 (Box 23)
    - Parks for Northern Virginia, 1950 (Box 23)
    - Recreation Development Program, 1954 (Box 23)
    - Potomac Nature Trails, 1965 (Box 23)
    - Management/Personnel Study, 1969 (Box 24)
    - History of the Park System, 1971 (Box 24)
    - Report on Arlington Visitors Program, 1979 (Box 24)
    - Report to the Recreation Advisory Committee (no date) (Box 24)
    - Hiking Opportunities in Arlington VA, Thomas W. Richards, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Regulations
    - Rules for Festivals, Fairs, etc. in Parks, and Bicycle Rules, 1955 (Box 24)
  - Consumer Publications
    - Guides to recreation and parks, 1958-59 (Box 24)
    - Public Information, rec classes, 1948-1960 (Box 24)
    - Guide to Gulf Branch Nature Trail, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Press Release
    - Petrified Log at Lubber Run, 1944 (Box 24)
- County Manager's Personal Files
  - Capital Improvement
    - Projections, 1960 (Box 24)
    - Projections, 1963 (Box 24)
    - Projections, 1964 (Box 24)
    - Projections, 1965 (Box 24)
    - Projections, 1966 (Box 24)
    - Projections, 1967 (Box 24)
    - Projections, 1968 (Box 24)
    - Projections, 1969 (Box 24)
    - Projections, 1974 (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous data, 1947-50 (scattered) (Box 24)
  - Community Projects and Clubs
    - Clean-up, Paint-up, Fix-up Campaign, 1939 (Box 24)
    - Centennial Celebration, Chamber of Commerce, 1946 (Box 24)
    - Coaster Car Race, Program & 4 Photos (See APPENDIX), 1949 (Box 24)
    - County Extension Work, VA Agricultural Extension, 1959 (Box 24)
    - County Extension Work, VA Agricultural Extension, 1960 (Box 24)
    - County Extension Work, VA Agricultural Extension, 1961 (Box 24)
    - Home Demonstration Clubs: Year Books, 1960, 1961, 1962 (Box 24)
    - Arlington County 4-H Year Book, 1965 (?) (Box 24)
    - Swimming program, 4 photos (See APPENDIX) (No documentation) (Box 24)
  - Finances
    - County Auditor, Financial Statements, 1932-1934 (Box 24)
    - Comparative Cost of Local Government, State Auditor, 1933 (Box 24)
    - Comparative Cost of Local Government, State Auditor, 1934 (Box 24)
    - Comparative Cost of Local Government, State Auditor, 1937 (Box 24)
    - Comparative Cost of Local Government, State Auditor, 1938 (Box 24)
    - Comparative Cost of Local Government, State Auditor, 1939 (Box 24)
    - Comparative Cost of Local Government, State Auditor, 1941 (Box 25)
    - Comparative Cost of Local Government, State Auditor, 1945 (Box 25)
    - Comparative Cost of Local Government, State Auditor, 1946 (Box 25)
    - Comparative Cost of Local Government, State Auditor, 1948 (Box 25)
    - Comparative Cost of Local Government, State Auditor, 1950 (Box 25)
    - Debt Structure, County of Arlington, Report, 1948 (Box 25)
    - Debt Structure, 1949 (Box 25)
    - Debt Structure, 1950 (Box 25)
    - Debt Structure, 1951 (Box 25)
    - Bonded Indebtedness of Virginia Towns, 1934 (Box 25)
    - Bonded Indebtedness of Virginia Cities, 1939 (Box 25)
    - Bonded Indebtedness of Virginia Cities, 1941 (Box 25)
    - Bonded Indebtedness of Virginia Cities, 1942 (Box 25)
    - Commissioner of Revenue's Reports, 1928, 29, 30, 31 (Box 25)
    - Credit Survey, Dunn & Bradstreet, 1948 (Box 25)
    - Sewer System Loan Agreement and Amendment, 1934-36 (Box 25)
    - Water & Sewer Systems, Costs, Charges, report, 1949 (Box 25)
    - Debt Survey of Arlington Co...U of Virginia, 1950 (Box 25)
    - Supplement to Debt Survey, Jul 1951: Bond Issue, Storm Sewer, Street, Highway, November 1951 (Box 25)
    - Supplement to Debt Survey, Nov 1951: School Bonds, July 1952 (Box 25)
    - Supplement to Debt Survey, July 1952: Park Bonds, December 1952 (Box 25)
    - Supplement to Debt Survey, Dec 1952: School Bonds, June 1953 (Box 25)
    - Bond Issue, Background Info, 1951 (Box 25)
    - Fee schedules, departmental, 1953-61 (scattered) (Box 25)
    - Revenue from Sources other than Taxation, Arlington County, 1953 (Box 25)
    - Occupancy Tax, Report to County Board, 1953 (Box 25)
    - Tax Comparison, Metro Area, 1954 (Box 25)
    - County Revenues, Report (by Revenue Item #), 1954 (Box 25)
    - Arlington County Finances, County Manager, 1955 (Box 25)
    - Tax Comparison, Metro Area, 1957 (Box 25)
    - Arlington County Finances, Transcript, L.L. Ecker-Racz to Committee of 100, 1955 (Box 25)
    - Tax info solicited from localities in Prince Georges County, 1957 (Box 26)
    - State Poll Taxes, Colored, List, 1957 (Box 26)
    - State Poll Taxes, Colored, List, 1959 (Box 26)
    - State Poll Taxes, Colored, List, 1961 (Box 26)
    - County Revenues, Catalog (by Revenue Item #), 1958 (Box 26)
    - Committee on County Expenditures, Report, 1959 (Box 26)
    - Financial Support Received by Arlington from the Commonwealth of Virginia - Report, 1962 (Box 26)
    - Financing Arlington's Local Government Report, 1970 (Box 26)
    - Budget memoranda, 1948-1974 (scattered) (Box 26)
    - Financial statistics, miscellaneous, 1936-1974 (scattered) (Box 26)
    - Plain Facts: An Arlington County Fiscal Profile, 1960-74, 1975 (Box 26)
    - Reports to Taxpayers, 1937, 1960, 1961, 1962, 1964 (Box 26)
    - Business & Professional License Tax Survey, University of Virginia (UVA) Memo #1, 1948 (Box 26)
    - Business & Professional License Tax Survey, UVA, Memo #2, 1948 (Box 26)
    - Business & Professional License Tax Survey, UVA, Memo #3, 1948 (Box 26)
    - Business & Professional License Tax Survey, UVA, Memo #4, 1948 (Box 26)
    - Business & Professional License Tax Survey, UVA, Memo #5, 1948 (Box 26)
    - Business & Professional License Tax Survey, UVA, Memo #6, 1948 (Box 26)
    - Business & Occupational License Taxes, Report, UVA, 1951 (Box 26)
  - Census Advisory Committee on State and Local Government Statistics (U.S. Department of Commerce)
    - Minutes & Background Materials, 1965 (Box 26)
    - Minutes & Background Materials, 1966 (Box 26)
    - Minutes & Background Materials, 1967 (Box 26)
    - Minutes & Background Materials, 1968 (Box 26)
    - Minutes & Background Materials, 1969 (Box 26)
    - Census, Correspondence, 1939, 1940, 1948 (Box 26)
  - "Hear and Discuss" Meetings - minutes, notes, 1979
    - Schedules and notes (Box 26)
    - Clerical group (Box 26)
    - Coalition of Public Employees (Box 26)
    - Firefighters (Box 27)
    - Pay and benefits (Box 27)
    - Life and medical insurance - background, no minutes (Box 27)
    - Managers (Box 27)
    - Police (Box 27)
    - Trades (Box 27)
  - Incorporation of Arlington
    - Possible Revenue Changes, League of VA Municipalities, 1937 (Box 27)
    - If Arlington Incorporates, Arlington Chamber of Commerce, 1945 (Box 27)
    - Charter of City of Arlington, House Bill #319, 1946 (Box 27)
    - City of Alexandria VA, Charter, 1950 (Box 27)
    - Commission on Incorporation, minutes, background, 1945-1959 (scattered) (Box 27)
    - Commission on Incorporation, compilation of data, 1950-1974 (scattered) (Box 27)
    - Personal Property Tax, collected data, 1951-1961 (Box 27)
    - Effects of Incorporation of Arlington County, Bureau of Public Administration, UVA, 1952 (Box 27)
    - The Effect of Incorporation on Arlington's Finances, County Manager, 1952 (Box 27)
    - Incorporation of Arlington, Report #3, Citizen's Study Commission, 1952 (Box 27)
    - Incorporation of Arlington, report summary, Citizen's Study Commission, 1952 (Box 27)
    - Tax Comparison Study, correspondence, background, 1954-1962 (scattered) (Box 27)
    - Tax Comparison Surveys (published) County Manager, 1954, 1957 (Box 27)
    - Tax Sales of Real Estate, studies, statistics, background, 1955-1956 (Box 27)
    - Fiscal Aspects of Land Use, study outline, reports, correspondence, 1955-1958 (Box 28)
    - Commission on Incorporation, general correspondence, clippings, 1958 (Box 28)
    - Commission on Incorporation, minutes & related correspondence, testimony, reports, 1958 (Box 28)
    - Commission on Incorporation, correspondence, Study Committee and UVA, 1958-1959 (Box 28)
    - Incorporation: Memo Series, U of Virginia to Arlington Commission on Incorporation, 1958-1959: #01: Role of Bur of Public Administration (Box 28)
    - #02: Annexation in Virginia (Box 28)
    - #03: Role and Content of a City Charter in Virginia (Box 28)
    - #04: Proposed Study Outline (Box 28)
    - #05: Effects of Incorporation on Government Structures (Box 28)
    - #06: The Place of the City in Virginia Government (Box 28)
    - #07: Special Law Charters in Conflict with General Law (Box 28)
    - #08: Cost of Constructing & Maintaining Highways (Box 28)
    - #09: Virginia Practice: Certain Municipal Officers (Box 28)
    - #10: Constitutional Basis of and Limitations on Charter (Box 28)
    - #11: Proposed Charter: City of Arlington (draft) (Box 28)
    - #12: Addendum to Staff Memo #11 (Box 28)
    - #14: Effects on State Financial Aid (Box 28)
    - #15: Easing the Impact of Highway Financing (Box 28)
    - #17: Effect on Borrowing & Long-Term Debt (Box 28)
    - #18: Box Score on Incorporation (Box 28)
    - #19: Arlington County Basic Law, Amendments to (Box 28)
    - #20: Arlington County Basic Law, Addendum (Box 28)
    - #21: Proposed Charter and Explanation Thereof (Box 28)
    - #22: Office of Mayor in Council-Manager Cities (Box 28)
    - #23: Referendum on Bond Issues (Box 28)
    - #24: Notaries Public During Period of Transition (Box 28)
    - #25: Selection of Judges of Courts Not of Record (Box 28)
    - #26: Final Report: Bureau of Public Administration to Commission (draft) (Box 28)
    - Charter, correspondence on hearings, clippings, 1959 (Box 28)
    - Draft Charter for City of Arlington, Commission on Incorporation, 1959 (Box 28)
    - Final Report & Proposed Charter for City of Arlington Commission on Incorporation, 1959 (Box 28)
    - City/County analysis, miscellaneous background, 1934-1977 (scattered) (Box 29)
    - City/County Analysis, Working Paper, Phase 1, and Summary, 1976 (Box 29)
    - City/County Analysis, Fiscal studies, correspondence, 1976, 1978, 1979 (Box 29)
    - Study of Local Government, House Doc #17, VA Advisory Legislative Council, 1977 (Box 29)
    - House Bill #63, models for local government correspondence, 1978 (Box 29)
    - City Charter Briefing Book, Arlington County Civic Federation, 1978 (Box 29)
    - Study Commission on City/County Form of Government, correspondence, membership, agendas, 1978-1979 (Box 29)
    - Study Committee, Governmental Structure, background, 1960/1979 (scattered) (Box 29)
    - House Bill 63, local government structure, 1978 (Box 29)
    - Senate Bill 46: Charter For County of Fairfax, '78 (Box 29)
  - Planning
    - License, Fort Myer Road, 1889 (Box 29)
    - Water and Sewerage, miscellaneous papers, 1926-1951 (scattered) (Box 29)
    - Petition, Abbey Mausoleum, Inc., 1930 (Box 29)
    - Streets and Highways, miscellaneous papers, 1930-1950 (scattered) (Box 29)
    - Braddock Light & Power Co., correspondence, petition, contract (street lights) 1932-1933 (Box 29)
    - Statistical reports, departmental, 1932-1944 (scattered) (Box 30)
    - Easement, Rosslyn storm sewer, 1934 (Box 30)
    - Reorganization of County Departments, miscellaneous correspondence, 1937-1955 (Box 30)
    - Arlington County VA Electric System, Preliminary Investigation, Wiley & Wilson, 1936 (Box 30)
    - Electric Light & Power Utilities, Public Ownership & Operations, Wiley & Wilson, 1938 (Box 30)
    - History of Arlington Writers' Project, 1939 (Box 30)
    - Functions, departmental, correspondence, reports, 1940-1950 (scattered) (Box 30)
    - Health Department, history, budget, correspondence, 1944-1951 (scattered) (Box 30)
    - Budget, Planning Division, recommendations, 1947-1948 (Box 30)
    - Police Department, miscellaneous correspondence, 1947-1950 (scattered) (Box 30)
    - Rosslyn Gas Co, Natural Gas Rates, J. Paul Blundon, 1949 (Box 30)
    - Storm Drain, Proposed, and Landscape Plan, George Mason Drive, Drawing & 8 Photos (See APPENDIX), 1949 (Box 30)
    - Civil Defense, County Managers' Meeting, 1950 (with photo of participants) (Box 30)
    - Major Thoroughfare Plan, Minority Report, John Coyle, 1960 (Box 30)
    - Potomac I-266 River Crossings, Analysis, 1964 (Box 30)
    - Improved Communications, Proposal, C&P Telephone, 1964 (Box 30)
    - Undergrounding Overhead Distribution Facilities, Study, Stone & Webster, 1974 (Box 30)
    - Proposed Cultural-Education Center, Interim Report 1965 (Box 30)
    - Data Processing in Arlington County VA, Department of Finance, 1965 (Box 30)
    - Rosslyn Area, Summary of Projects, 1966 (Box 30)
    - Map: Relief Sanitary Sewers Needed as a Result of Hurricane Agnes, 1973 (Box 30)
    - Initial planning report on Comprehensive Employment and Training Act (CETA), 1974 (Box 30)
    - Transportation Sys for Senior Citizens, Grant Award, 1972 (Box 30)
    - Recommendations, 208 Draft Plan, Water Resources, Citizen Advisory Committee, 1978 (Box 30)
    - Washington Metro Water Quality Management Plan (208 Draft) Hearing Summary, 1978 (Box 30)
    - Washington Metro Water Quality Management Plan (208 Draft) Staff Response, 1978 (Box 30)
    - Washington Metro Water Quality Management Plan (208 Draft) Revisions, 1978 (Box 30)
  - Insurance
    - Fire Insurance Survey, Schools, C.W. Clever, Agent (24 photos, See APPENDIX), 1932 (Box 31)
    - Fire Insurance Survey, various properties, C.W. Clever, Agent (15 photos, See APPENDIX), 1932 (Box 31)
    - Administration of County Insurance Program, Report, FY 58 (Box 31)
    - Fire & Extended Coverage Inquiry, 1959 (Box 31)
    - Insurance Analysis Report, Insurance Buyers' Council, 1959 (Box 31)
    - Insurance Analysis Report, 1960 (Box 31)
    - Insurance Analysis Report, 1961 (Box 31)
    - Insurance Analysis Report, 1962 (Box 31)
    - Insurance Analysis Report, 1963 (Box 31)
    - Insurance Analysis Report, 1964 (Box 31)
    - Insurance Analysis Report, 1965 (Box 31)
    - Insurance Analysis Report, 1966 (Box 31)
    - Insurance Analysis Report, 1967 (Box 31)
    - Insurance Analysis Report, 1971 (Box 31)
    - Self-Insurance, Proposal, Insurance Buyers' Council, 1964 (Box 31)
    - Risk Management & Comm'l Insurance, Analysis Report, Insurance Buyers' Council, 1972 (Box 31)
  - County Manager's Personal Notes (various subjects) with background material
    - 1967 (Box 31)
    - 1968 (Box 31)
    - 1969 (Box 31)
    - 1970 (Box 31)
    - 1971 (Box 32)
    - 1972 (Box 32)
    - 1973 (Box 32)
  - Random Notes to the County Board (various subjects) with background material
    - 1971 (Box 32)
    - 1972 (January-August) (Box 32)
    - 1972 (September-December) (Box 32)
    - 1973 (Box 32)
    - 1974 (Box 32)
    - 1975 (Box 32)
  - Historical materials
    - Report of the Virginia and District of Columbia Boundary Commission, 1935 (Box 32)
    - District of Columbia and Virginia Boundary Line Report, 1936 (Box 32)
    - Arlington County Water System, A. T. Lundberg, 1938 (reprint) (Box 32)
    - Inventory of Some Old Records of Arlington County, Meredith B. Colket, Jr., 1952 (Box 32)
    - Historic Arlington, 1608-1932, Ludwell Lee Montague, 1968 (Box 32)
    - History of Three Guns and the Ship's Bell (without date or author) (Box 32)
    - The Growth of a City Government: An Enumeration of Detroit's Municipal Activities, Lent D. Upson, 1931 (Box 32)
  - Laws affecting county government
    - Brief on Behalf of Arlington County (Alexandria vs Arlington), annexation, 1928 (Box 33)
    - The Lanham Act, as amended, National Housing Agency, 1943 (Box 33)
    - County Manager Charters and Laws, National Municipal League, 1949 (Box 33)
    - County Manager Charters and Laws, 1954 (Box 3)
    - County Manager Government in Virginia, 1964 Code of Virginia, Chapter 13 (Box 33)
  - County regulations
    - Building Code Ordinance, hearings, 1935 (Box 33)
    - County Manager's Hornbook, 1962 (Box 33)
    - Dog Warden Position (draft), 1959 (Box 33)
    - Supplying Ice to County Field Crews, Survey, 1959 (Box 33)
    - Dog Tag Applications, 1960, 1962 (Box 33)
    - County Agencies, various, 1964-1966 (Box 33)
    - Personnel, 1964-1975 (Box 33)
    - Public Property, 1963, 1965 (Box 33)
    - Public Works, 1962, 1966 (Box 33)
    - Reorganization, 1963 (Box 33)
    - Welfare and Health, 1962-1964 (Box 33)
    - Real Property - Assessment & Appeal, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Regulations, miscellaneous correspondence, notes, 1938-1950 (Box 33)
  - Speeches, Bert W. Johnson, County Manager
    - 1962-1964 (Box 33)
    - 1965-1967 (Box 33)
    - 1968-1971 (Box 33)
  - References on County Government
    - County Management, Wylie Kilpatrick, ca 1930 (Box 33)
    - Change in Form of County Government, Civic Federation Committee (with news clips), 1930 (Box 33)
    - Report of Commission on County Government, Senate Doc #3, 1931 (Box 33)
    - Six Years of Managership in Arlington County, VA, National Municipal Review, 1937 (Box 33)
    - County Government in Virginia, UVA, 1942 (Box 34)
    - Ten Years of County Manager Government in Virginia, George W. Spicer, UVA Extension, 1945 (Box 34)
    - Fifteen Years of County Manager Government in Virginia, George W. Spicer, UVA Extension, 1951 (Box 34)
    - Table of Organization of Government of Arlington County, 1953 (with directory of county officials, 1973) (Box 34)